# **Turner Emmanuel**

## Senior Project Manager

- New York, NY 10162
- (469) 238-5645
- turneremmanuel800@gmail.com

Senior Project Manager with 8years of experience in boosting warehouse profitability by 50% for multiple E-Commerce retailers & Fintech. Completed all large scale programs ahead of schedule and created value-added campaigns to help organizations achieve dynamic goals.

A diligent worker with strong communication skills, task prioritization in optimizing resources and workflows, planning events, agile milestones and creating well-sequenced processes to ensure effective program execution. A leader with the willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals.



#### **Skills**

- Leadership Skills {Coach, Charismatic, Servant, Transformational}
- SDLC {Agile & Waterfall}
- Requirement Gathering & Client Facing
- Effective Communication Skills & Effective Decision Making
- Program and Strategic Management
- Team Building & Conflict Resolution
- Programming Skills {HTML, CSS, JAVA, PHP, PYTHON, AJAX, WORDPRESS, SQL}
- SWOT, GAP, MOST, PESTLE Analysis
- Forecast, Budget & Risk Management
- UI/UX Designs
- AWS, Azure & GCP Cloud



# **Work History**

2020-10 - Current

## Senior Project Manager

Bank Of America, Austin, TX

 Led and planned projects using appropriate tools and techniques, including Technology platforms used by client facing employees, change management tools, and risk and issue management tools to ensure efficient and effective project completion.

- Developed detailed work plans, including work breakdown structures, project milestones, risk assessment/management plans, staffing needs and project timelines.
- Monitored project time, scope, budget and billable rates to ensure alignment with contract and project documentation while ensuring proper documentation of business requirements, process flows, design and other business analysis deliverables
- Compiled status updates for Sr Management and Steering Group Meetings. Report on the completed activities, ongoing activities, risks, upcoming milestones, and decisions (amongst others).
- Ensuring quality is considered throughout delivery, including QA and UAT to
  ensure outputs are thoroughly tested and proven before deployment to
  customers and handed over to support.
- Technical leadership during project planning and delivery for all aspects of company technology delivery services using: Agile SLDC and Web portal and API development, Data Ingestion, data management for reporting, Data file transfers, Database and IT Systems.
- Managed design or redesign of processes or projects using Six Sigma methodologies. Integrates best practices with process design to ensure continuous process improvement. Built action plans and drives execution.
- Develop and control deadlines, budgets and activities. Track ongoing spend in relation to the budget, Applied change, risk and resource management.

#### HealthCare IT Project Manager

United Health Group, USA, Houston, TX

- Facilitate all Agile ceremonies, including sprint planning, daily stand-ups, sprint reviews, and retrospectives, ensuring adherence to Scrum framework and collaborated with product owners, business stakeholders, and development teams to define project goals, scope, and backlog items specifically
- Identified resources needed and assigns individual responsibilities and coordinating quality assurance procedure then also ensuring project documents are complete, current, and stored appropriately.
- Facilitated conflict resolution and help teams make decisions by fostering a
  collaborative and inclusive environment and monitoring and tracking
  project progress, ensuring that the team is meeting sprint goals,
  deliverables, and timelines.
- Stayed current with industry trends, best practices, and advancements in EHR solutions to drive continuous improvement and innovation, and also compiling reports on project progress, budget utilization, and other relevant metrics.
- Estimated project costs and manage budgets effectively then allocating resources efficiently to optimize productivity and meet project objectives.
- Fostered a positive and collaborative team environment and assigning tasks, set deadlines, and monitor team progress towards project goals in Jira while ensuring effective communication and collaboration.

2017-08 - 2020-09

2016-08 - 2017-09

 Reported on an overall integrated delivery plan, raising any risks, developing a mitigation plan, and escalating issues appropriately to respective stakeholders and also displaying enthusiastic, energetic, determined, and positive work ethic.

## Scrum Master/Agile Product Owner

Walmart, Dallas, TX

- Mentored and elevated onshore and offshore team morale while overseeing successful migration of 290 apps to AWS cloud and Microsoft Azure.
- Created and managed epics delivered to development team.
   Additionally, organized and lead epic review sessions with both design and technical resources while continued to be involved in epics through delivery, included discussions with business leads, sprint reviews and UAT.
- Supported Release Management and version control by coordinating activities across business and technical teams.
- Wrote User Stories while also leading Daily Standup, Sprint Review, Retrospectives, Spring Planning and Backlog Refinement while simultaneously defining user stories that are ready for development team with right "definition of done".
- Collaborated with software development team on design approach, owned writing of functional specifications and obtained quality assurance estimate while approving all change orders and non-standard proposals related to product.
- Gathered and managed detailed business, functional and technical requirements; work with business stakeholders, and applicable technical staff to identify feature details and administered them in Scrum Product Backlog.



## **Education**

2015-08

Master of Science: Computer Engineering Technology University of Leeds - Woodhouse, Leeds LS2 9JT, United Kingdom

2010-09 - 2014-07

Bachelor of Science: Management Information Systems
 Covenant University - Lagos, Nigeria



### Software

Version 1

Jira & Confluence

Monday.com

Microsoft Visio & Power BI

Miro & Retrospective Boards

SaaS & PaaS Tools

Salesforce



English

French



2021-02

2020-11

2020-02

2019-05

2018-07

2017-03

2016-12

2016-04

# **Certifications**

- 2022-09 International Scrum Institute (SMAC)
  - Program Management Professional (PgMP)
  - SAFe Scrum Master (SSM)
  - Salesforce Certified Associate Certification (SCAC)
  - Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO®)
  - Certified Business Analysis Professional {CBAP}
  - Advanced Certified ScrumMaster {A-CSM®}
  - Professional Scrum Master I {PSM I}
  - Project Management Professional (PMP)